世界的政治格局已经到了
The political situation in the world has now reached a stage
为表达对日本侵略行为的愤慨并对其施压
美国总统罗斯福于1937年10月5日
在芝加哥发表了著名的"隔离演说"
文明的根基
where the very foundations of civilization
都受到严重威胁的阶段
are seriously threatened.
战争就是一种传染病
War is a contagion.
世界的和平
The peace of the world,
包括我们自己在内的
the welfare and security of every nation,
各个国家的福祉和安全
including our own,
都受到这个传染病的威胁
is being threatened by that very thing.
谁也不能幻想美国可以幸免于难
Let no one imagine that America will escape.
是的  我们誓要远离战争
Yes, we are determined to keep out of war.
然而  我们却无法保证自己
Yet, we cannot insure ourselves
不受战争的灾难性影响
against the disastrous effects of war,
以及参战的危险
and the dangers of involvement.
本片真实描述了导致美国历史上最重要海战的一系列事件
扭转了太平洋战争局势的一天
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     Margaery  glida kathy567  海云生
翻译     贝七  VioletCheng  nemonini
翻译     盐湖凉开水  TracyOY  刺罗森林
校对     Sakura的小书包
时间轴   西·查  Ans  知之
时间轴   浅野忠信推·浪影  紫夏
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔诚荐
这太他妈扯淡了
This is bloody ridiculous.
你们大英帝国不就是建立在扯淡传统上的吗
Wasn't your empire built on ridiculous traditions?
别为他们辩护  莱顿
Don't defend them, Layton.
你虽然会说他们的语言
You might speak their language,
但他们还是觉得你是野蛮人
but they still think you're a barbarian.
说实话
Be honest.
你走了之后不会想念这个地方吗
You won't miss this place when you're gone?
1937年12月4日
东京  清澄庭园
得了吧
Oh, please.
下次再看到这帮混蛋的时候
The next time I see the little buggers,
我希望是通过大口径舰炮的瞄准具
I hope it's through the sights of a 14-inch gun.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我谨代表大英帝国
On behalf of the British Empire,
感谢山本大将的
I wish to thank Admiral Yamamoto
盛情邀请
for this invitation.
愿我们两国齐心协力共筑海上和平
May our nations work together to maintain peace on the seas.
你不喜欢喝威士忌吗
我也可以问您同样的问题  大将
我有可靠消息说您杯子里的是茶
这是中国的老套路
你在日本期间还学会了什么
我只是个助理海军武官
所以我知道你一定有想法
Which is why I know that you must have an opinion.
我曾经就是我国驻华盛顿的海军武官
I was once our naval attaché in Washington.
就在您哈佛毕业之后
After you went to Harvard.
和你一样  我当时认为
Like you, I thought there was value
潜在对手是值得学习的
in studying a potential adversary.
有传言说  您告诉首相
There's a rumor that you told the prime minister
日本没法赢下与美国的战争
that Japan can't win a war with the United States.
我说的是我们赢不了长期的战争
I said we couldn't win a long war.
还有传言说您有生命危险
There's another rumor that your life is in danger.
民族主义者认为您太温和了
That the nationalists think you're too moderate
把您定为暗杀的目标
and have targeted you for assassination.
日本正处于十字路口
Japan is at a crossroads.
我们受到侵略中国的鼓舞
We are emboldened by our invasion of China
渴望成为世界强国
and eager to become a world power.
然而我们80%的石油却要从贵国进口
Yet we get 80% of our oil from your country.
如果供给受到威胁
If that supply is threatened,
会迫使我们采取严厉措施
it will force us into drastic measures.
您想让我把这个信息传递给华盛顿
You want me to pass this information along to Washington?
别把我们逼急了
Don't push us into a corner.
必须给我们这些更理智的人
You must give those of us who are more reasonable
一个占据主导的机会
a chance to carry the day.
谁都不想开战
Nobody wants a war.
再见  莱顿先生
Sayonara, Layton Sang.
再见
Sayonara.
四年后  世界大战爆发了
日本入侵了中国  希特勒的闪电战席卷了欧洲
美国已正式宣布中立
决战中途岛
1941年12月7日
美国海军企业号
珍珠岛以西225公里处
加把劲  跳高点  娘炮们
Come on. Step it up, ladies!
让出飞行甲板
Clear the flight deck.
快
Let's go.
准备防备冲击
Prepare to brace!
您为什么不用副翼  长官
Why aren't you using the flaps, sir?
因为总有一天我们要在
Because someday we might have to land
副翼被打掉的情况下降落
with our flaps shot away.
还不如现在就练习
So we might as well practice now.
亨特少尉以前不是这么飞的吧
This isn't how Ensign Hunt used to fly.
所以亨特少尉现在待在圣地亚哥数海鸥呢
Which is why Ensign Hunt is now counting seagulls in San Diego
而跟我在飞机上的是你
and you're here with me.
看来我们的油箱也被击中了
Looks like we got hit in our fuel tank, too.
别这样  长官
Please don't, sir.
这以后也许能救你的命  默里
This might save your life one day, Murray.
引擎就要失灵了
Engine's about to die.
准备回收飞机
Stand by to recover aircraft.
贝斯特在搞什么  他疯了
What the hell is Best doing? He's out of the groove.
引擎看起来像是熄火了
It looks like his engine cut out.
他这是耍特技  还是有麻烦了
Is it a stunt, or is he in trouble?
我也不知道
I don't know.
但他肯定会一如既往地钩住第一根线的
But he's going to hit the first wire like always.
那个角度可不行
Not with that angle.
我们怎么侧过去了
Why are we sideways?
降低速度  免得把甲板撞个洞出来
To shave speed so we don't put a hole in the deck.
最好别坠机
Better not crash that damn plane.
坚持住  小子
Hey, hang in there, kid.
马上就要到家了
We're almost home.
防备冲击
Brace!
你是想上军事法庭吗
Are you trying to get court marshalled?
电路有点问题
I had electrical issue.
谁都可能遇上这种情况
Could have happened to anyone.
表现不错
Good job.
你要说服的人可不是我
Well, it's not me you have to convince.
麦克拉斯基准备好要收拾你了
McClusky's about ready to have your ass.
那我自己送上门去
Then I'll take it upstairs to the old man.
他知道会发生什么
He knows what's coming.
我们这次航行
That's why we've been flying
一直在飞双倍的侦察任务就是因为这个
double scouting missions this whole trip.
要飞啊
Going somewhere?
对  他们今早要把整个中队
Yeah, they're sending the whole squadron
都送到珍珠港
into Pearl this morning.
我中午就能跟罗伊在海滩上喝啤酒了
And I'll be drinking a beer on the beach with Roy by noon.
不带我吗
And I'm not coming?
不带  麦克拉斯基把第六侦察机中队都留下了
No. McClusky's holding back Scouting Six.
很可能就是因为你太混球了
It's probably 'cause you're such an asshole.
你不就喜欢我这点吗
Yeah, you're lovin' this, right?
早上好  长官  飞机找到了
Morning, sir. Aircraft is spotted.
对米勒温柔点
Hey, take it easy on Miller.
他今天早上够受的了
He's having a tough morning.
这是我最后一天执行海上任务  长官
It's my last day of sea duty, sir.
我是我们无线电班组唯一一个没坠过机的
And I'm the only one from my radio class who hasn't crashed.
别担心  米勒
Don't worry, Miller.
我相信迪金森先生能把你
I'm sure even Mr. Dickinson can fly you
平安送到珍珠港  不会让你掉海里的
from here to Pearl without getting you wet.
我和罗伊
Me and Roy,
会在海滩给你洒点啤酒的
we'll pour a little beer out on the beach for ya.
罗伊·皮尔斯上尉
美国海军
喝一杯蓝带啤酒
美国海军亚利桑那号
珍珠港
你们这帮小子真悠闲
Well, you boys are taking your sweet time.
牧师随时会到
Chaplain's gonna be here any minute.
今天又是一个大热天  长官
It's another hot one, sir.
-你是在抱怨吗  萨利  -不是  长官
- Are you complaining, Sully? - No, sir.
我就是想不明白  既然我不信上帝
I just can't help wondering why I have to set up chairs for church,
为什么还要为礼拜仪式摆椅子
even though I don't believe in God.
因为你唯一的信仰就是寻花问柳
Well, that's because your only religion is chasing tail.
海军花钱可不是雇你干这个的
And the Navy ain't gonna pay you for that.
敌机来袭
Incoming!
芭芭拉
Barbara!
芭芭拉  过来
Barbara, come here!
快过来  宝贝
Come on, sweetheart.
把伤员抬到甲板下面去
Get the wounded below deck!
其他人  进入战斗岗位
Everyone else, battle stations!
趴下
Get down!
去教堂吗
Comin' to church?
我得去办公室
I have to go to the office.
今天是周日
It's Sunday.
你工作太卖力了
You work too hard.
这里是莱顿住处
Layton residence.
我这就出来找你
I'll meet you outside.
埃德温  怎么了
Edwin, what's happening?
日军正在袭击我们
The Japanese are attacking us.
你联系上办公室了吗
Did you reach the office?
没有  总机打不进去
No. The switchboard was jammed.
开车
Go.
萨利  起来  快点
Sully, get up! Come on!
我们得到炮火射击指挥仪那去
We need to get to the gun directors.
他们打得太低了
They're firing way too low.
找掩护  趴下
Take cover! Get down!
快开车
Drive!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我们得下船  快
We have to get off the ship. Come on.
快点  小子
Hurry up, kid.
我们得跳过去
We gotta jump.
掉进那水里  你就死定了
You go in that water, you're dead.
萨利  你先过  萨利
Sully! You first, Sully!
我做不到  我的手...
I can't! My hands...
你想活吗
You wanna live?
想活就到那艘船上去  听到了吗
You get to that goddamned ship, you hear me?
怎么回事  长官
What is it, sir?
看起来海岸炮兵都疯了
Looks like Coastal Artillery went stark mad.
肯定有人要受重罚了
I bet you somebody's gonna catch hell for it.
遭受攻击
Incoming!
米勒  打破无线电静默  枪用起来
Miller, break radio silence. Get that gun working!
珍珠港遭受攻击  这不是玩笑
Pearl is under attack. This is no shit.
米勒  你没事吧
Miller, you okay?
米勒  跳伞
Miller, bail out!
米勒  米勒
Miller! Miller!
米勒
Miller!
到底什么情况
What the hell is going on?
珍珠港在射击我们的人  长官
Pearl is shooting at our guys, sir.
那么或许不是珍珠港
Then maybe it isn't Pearl.
联系迪金森
Look, call Dickinson.
我们收到他汇报遭受攻击  然后就没音了
We had a transmission that he was under attack and then nothing.
珍珠港遭遇空袭  这不是演习
长官
Sir.
拿给司令看
Get this to the admiral.
快过去  萨利
Keep going, Sully.
卧倒
Get down!
拜托
Come on.
曾试图警告我们的人来了
There's the man who tried to warn us.
莱顿  你是对的  这么说不知道你满意没有
If it's any satisfaction to you, Layton, you were right.
长官  无论如何这都不会让我满意
Sir, it's no satisfaction to me whatsoever.
混蛋
You bastard.
长官  他们要去哪
Sir, where are they going?
回母舰
Back to their carriers.
开车去无线电测向仪那里  然后跟我汇报
Drive out to the radio direction finder and report back to me.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
哈尔西司令到舰
Admiral Halsey on deck.
珍珠港有发现吗
Pearl found something?
情报人员成功获取攻击舰队的走向线
Intelligence managed to get a line of bearing on the attacking fleet.
但那是双向读数
But it's a bilateral reading.
日本人要么在343度
The Japanese are either at 343 degrees
要么在163度
or 163 degrees.
老天
For Christ's sake.
珍珠港遭受攻击  而我们甚至不知道
Pearl is under attack and we don't even know
那些混蛋在南面还是北面
if the bastards are north or south?
陆军轰炸机还报告在这里可能发现一艘舰只
Army bombers also reported a possible ship sighting here.
我们就赌
We're gonna place our bet
是在这里
right there.
我们获取了日军舰队可能的位置
We have a possible location on the Jap fleet.
到185方位飞行搜索
Fly a grid on bearing 185.
如果遇到敌军
If you make contact,
贝斯特及其部下会放烟幕弹
Best and his men will put down a smokescreen
然后鱼雷轰炸机就开始行动
and then the torpedo bombers will make their runs.
林赛指挥
Lindsey has command.
去他的烟幕弹
To hell with smoke.
让我带着真炸弹去炸了他们的航母
Let me go after those carriers with a real bomb.
鱼雷能炸沉船  炸弹不能
Torpedoes sink ships, not bombs,
而且我的人需要烟幕
and my men need a screen.
即使你们飞得足够近
Yeah, even if you get close enough,
你们那鱼雷也没用
your torpedoes don't work.
-那是谣言  -没错  是谣言
- That's a rumor. - Yeah, it's a rumor,
因为那破玩意从未被试验过
'cause the damn things have never been tested.
小日本在杀害我们的朋友
Look, the Japs are out there killing our friends.
让我把230公斤的炸弹
Let me put a 500-pound bomb
直接投入他们的烟囱
right down their goddamn smokestack.
我们不会因为你想报仇就改变战术
We're not changing tactics just because you want revenge.
去打小日本吗  长官
Going after the Japs, sir?
是的  我们要用烟把他们熏死
Yeah, we're gonna smoke 'em to death.
日本人在各条战线上发动袭击
Japanese are attacking on multiple fronts.
我们从击落的日军飞机获取了无线电日志
We captured a radio log from a downed Japanese plane.
日军舰队的六艘航母都对我们展开攻击
They hit us with all six of their fleet carriers.
好在他们没摧毁我们的油罐
At least they didn't destroy our oil tanks.
那样整个舰队都得撤退到西海岸
The whole fleet would have had to withdraw to the West Coast.
莱顿  你是我所知最好的情报人员
You are the best intelligence officer I've ever known, Layton.
他们也可能为此而处罚你
They'll probably burn you for this, too.
如果没有的话
But if they don't,
向我保证
swear to me,
你会让下一任司令听你的
you'll make the next man in this chair listen to you.
有发现吗  长官
See anything, sir?
连条鲸鱼都没看到
Not even a goddamn whale.
第六轰炸机中队十号  我是第六鱼雷机中队一号
Six baker 10, this is six torpedo one.
带我们回企业号
Lead us back to Enterprise.
第六鱼雷机中队一号  你们的飞行员
Six torpedo one, your pilots aren't trained
没接受过夜间载弹降落训练
for a night carrier landing with live ordnance.
去珍珠港降落
Go land at Pearl.
我们无法越过那些山
We can't clear the mountains.
带我们回企业号  上尉
Take us back to Enterprise, lieutenant.
这是命令
That's an order.
第六鱼雷机中队一号  我要把储烟箱扔了
Six torpedo one, I'm dropping my smoke tanks
然后飞回企业号
and returning to Enterprise.
如果你想  就跟着我
Follow me if you want.
我们收到珍珠港的消息
We got word from Pearl.
日军舰队在北面  不在南面
The Jap fleet was north, not south.
该死的
God damn it!
好样的  伙计
Good job, man.
林赛  我担心的正是这个
Lindsey, this is what I was afraid of.
你一个部下差点炸了航母
One of your men almost blows up the damn carrier,
因为你们太害怕飞去珍珠港会被击落
because you were too afraid to get shot down flying into Pearl.
需要我提醒你我是你的上级吗  上尉
Do I have to remind you that I am your superior officer, lieutenant?
你要拿军衔当挡箭牌吗
You gonna hide behind your rank?
留着怒气打小日本去
Save it for the Japs.
我们现在在战争中  麦克拉斯基
We're at war now, McClusky.
-那个家伙搞砸就会有人死  -听我说
- When that guy screws up, people die! - Listen to me.
你想继续飞行吗
You wanna keep flying?
我建议你收收牛仔脾气
I suggest you knock off the cowboy bullshit.
走吧  默里
Come on, Murray.
天啊
Jesus.
他们在做什么
What are they doing?
船翻时  甲板下的人可能会被困在里面
When she went over, everyone below deck was probably trapped inside.
亚利桑那号上有你认识的人吗
Did you know anyone aboard Arizona?
有
Yeah,
我在军官学校的室友
my roommate from the Academy.
罗伊·皮尔斯上尉
Lieutenant Roy Pearce.
听说你跳伞逃离了一架完好的飞机
I heard you jumped out of a perfectly good plane.
飞机当时着火了
Well, it was on fire.
操纵装置还失灵
And the controls were dead.
米勒呢
Where's Miller?
可恶
Hell.
是啊
Yeah.
安在大门边
Ann's by the gate.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah, I'm all right.
-今晚回家  -我倒想
- Come home tonight. - I wish.
我们补充完燃料就会起航
We sail as soon as we're refueled.
我希望你和巴尔布回你父母在泽西的家
Look, I want you and Barb to go back to your parents' place in Jersey.
-不  -这里不安全
- No. - It's not safe here.
每个人都说这场仗会打很久
Everyone is saying this is gonna be a long war.
-万一...  -你不能把我们送回泽西
- What if... - You're not shipping us off to Jersey
就这么定了
and that's final.
你和莎拉谈过吗
Did you talk to Sarah?
罗伊在亚利桑那号上吗
Was Roy aboard the Arizona?
是的
Yes.
我们在各个医院找他  但还没找到
We're checking all the hospitals, but nothing yet.
告诉她我会找到他
Tell her I'll find him.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我听说袭击发生时你和皮尔斯上尉在一起
I heard you were with Lieutenant Pearce during the attack.
萨利
Sully...
他怎么了
what happened to him?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们已经尽力而为了
We're doing our best.
但各种残肢断臂被枕套裹着送来
But they've been bringing body parts... in pillow cases.
人太多了
There's too many.
他是金发
He was a blond guy.
高个  可能穿着军官制服
Tall. Probably wearing an officer's uniform.
军官在这边
Officers are down here.
还有其他线索吗
Is there anything else you can give me?
识别特征  纹身
Identifying features? Tattoos?
他应该戴着我们军官学校的毕业戒指
Well, he would have been wearing our class ring from Annapolis.
我们...
We...
在他被送来时从他身上取下了这个
took this off the body when he came in.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry.
你和他待一会吧
I'll give you a moment.
1941年12月7日
December 7th, 1941...
珍珠港事件次日美国总统罗斯福于国会发表演说
宣布对日开战  太平洋战争至此全面爆发
必须铭记这个耻辱的日子
a date which will live in infamy.
美利坚合众国
The United States of America
受到了日本帝国海空军
was suddenly and deliberately attacked
蓄意的突袭
by naval and air forces of the Empire of Japan.
美国当时与该国处于和平状态
The United States was at peace with that nation...
并且在日本的请求下...
and, at the solicitation of Japan...
关掉
仍在与其政府
was still in conversation
进行对话...
with its government and its...
怎么了
我们唤醒了一个沉睡的巨人
并让他的内心坚定不移
夏威夷之旅愉快吗
我让南云找到他们的航母并摧毁他们的燃料罐
但他拒绝了
真是个致命的错误
这本会耗费美国人一年时间来使珍珠港恢复运行
你打算什么时候把南云从指挥位置撤下来
南云击沉了美军的战列舰
所有人都认为他是英雄
总有一天那个老蠢货会犯下更大的错
进去以后别说这种话
我们在陆军面前必须要团结
我不是南云
珍珠港之战是一场伟大的胜利
但是...
如果给美国人喘息之机  他们会占上风
因此我们必须通过摧毁他们的航母  对他们进行毁灭性的打击
恭喜您  长官
Congratulations, sir.
您是领导海军的正确人选
You're the right man to run the Navy.
他们一遇到麻烦
When they get in trouble,
就会派出不好惹的家伙
they send for the sons of bitches.
我们的首要任务必须是
Our priority must be...
夺取我们所需的资源
这是陆军的任务
而海军的任务
就是带我们过去  再带我们回来
太平洋上的形势
The situation in the Pacific is far worse
远比所报告的糟糕
than has been reported.
我们有三艘航母
We have three carriers.
日军有十艘
The Japs have ten.
我们一艘能用的战列舰都没有  而他们有九艘
We have zero functional battleships, they have nine.
他们有更多的巡洋舰  轰炸机  战斗机
They have more cruisers, more bombers, more fighters, and...
他们的很多装备都更先进
much of their equipment is more modern.
我们只能指望现有的兵力
We'll just have to count on the men that we have out there
可以抵挡得住
to hold the line.
新任司令的工作可真不好做
I don't envy the new commander.
是我  对吧
It's me, isn't it?
总统亲自指定了你
The president asked for you himself.
他说你应该前往珍珠港  留在那里
He said that you should get the hell out to Pearl and stay there
直到我们的舰队驶入东京湾
until our ships sail into Tokyo Bay.
欢迎接手这个世上最艰难的任务
Welcome to the most difficult job in the world.
陆军把我们卷入了这场战争
现在却希望我们载着他们到处跑
暂时而已  情况会改变的
我希望你开始起草我们讨论过的行动计划
I want you to start drawing
中途岛
全体注意  立正
Detail. A-ten-hut!
预备
Ready.
瞄准
Aim.
开枪
Fire.
瞄准
Aim.
开枪
Fire.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
开枪
Fire.
节哀顺变
I'm so sorry.
罗伊想成为像你一样的飞行员
Roy wanted to be a pilot like you.
但我劝他放弃了
But I talked him out of it.
我说太危险了
I said it was too dangerous.
下场葬礼上再见
I'll see you at the next funeral.
你不必出席的
You don't have to go.
我要去
Yes, I do.
我们是一家人
We're family.
我想说
I just wanna say...
罗伊·皮尔斯是我认识的
Roy Pearce was one of the finest bastards
最好的混蛋之一
that I've ever met.
我可以谈他谈上一个小时
And I could talk about the man for an hour.
但我应该把这任务留给你们这些
But I think that's a job I'll leave up to one of you boys
和他一起进了军官学校的小伙们
that went to the Academy with him.
怎么样
What do you say?
好  我可不能让某个开鱼雷机的为罗伊致辞
Yeah, well, I can't let some torpedo jockey speak for Roy.
尤其是没优秀到能从企业号上起飞的家伙
Especially one not good enough to fly from Enterprise.
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
刚进军官学校那年的夏天  我  罗伊还有迪基
Summer after plebe year, me, Roy and Dickie
去探望了住在五大湖区的罗伊的叔叔
went up to visit Roy's uncle, up in the Great Lakes.
当年的禁酒令最为严厉
It was the peak of Prohibition,
所以有天晚上  我们决定航行到加拿大
so one night, we decide to sail to Canada
买一桶啤酒
to buy a keg of beer.
在我们回去的路上  太阳马上就要升起时
On our way back, right before the sun comes up,
风停了
the wind dies.
所以我们就
So, there we are,
漂浮在了湖中央
just floating in the middle of the lake,
等着边境巡逻队出现救我们
waiting for the Border Patrol to show up.
我说我们应该把酒丢掉  但罗伊...
I said we should just ditch the booze, but Roy...
迪基
Hey, Dickie,
罗伊说了什么
what did Roy say?
"想都别想
"Hell, no.
我们要喝光"
We'll drink it all."
罗伊曾是我的伴郎
Roy was my best man.
他是我女儿的教父
He was the godfather to my daughter.
我原以为将来
I thought someday...
我们会一起坐在门廊上  喝着啤酒
we'd be on a porch, drinking beers,
对我们在大战中的表现大肆吹嘘
telling lies about what we did in the big war.
敬罗伊
To Roy.
我的天
Man, oh, man.
你怎么让我喝了这么多
Why'd you make me drink so much?
你可能得送我回家了  亲爱的
You might have to carry me home, darling.
该死  海岸巡逻队
Oh, shit. Shore Patrol.
不  那是上将的旗帜
No, that's the admiral's flag.
我猜是新任司令
Hey, I bet it's the new commander.
你觉得是谁
Who do you think it is?
看着像尼米兹
That looks like Nimitz.
听说他是个忠将
I hear he's true-blue.
尼米兹
Hey, Nimitz!
你什么时候才派我们去打小日本
When are you going to let us at those Japs?
对不起  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
要我去记下他们的名字吗
Do you want me to get their names?
不用
No.
他好像听到了
I think he might have heard you.
我很高兴至少还有小伙子斗志满满
I'm glad at least some of the boys still want to fight.
欢迎来到珍珠港  长官
Welcome to Pearl, sir.
我是莱顿少校
I'm Lieutenant Commander Layton.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
那您应该会理解我的请求
Well, then you'll understand my request.
我想被调到一艘驱逐舰上
I wish to be reassigned to a destroyer.
你是不是试图警告过前任司令
Didn't you try to warn my predecessor
可能有突袭
about the impending attack?
不完全是
Well, not exactly.
我说的是我们跟丢了敌军的航母
I said that we had lost track of the enemy carriers
需要做好防备
and needed to be prepared.
我应该更强硬点的
I should've pushed harder.
我想  这个教训
A lesson, I assume,
你已经永生难忘了
you have taken to heart.
长官
Sir...
我是要为美国史上最大情报失误
I'm the intelligence officer responsible for overseeing the greatest
负责的情报官员
intelligence failure in American history.
关上门
Close the door.
现在士气处于最低点
Morale is at an all-time low
但完全可以理解
and for good reason.
日军正以骇人的速度
The Japanese are advancing on all fronts
在各条战线上推进
at a terrifying pace.
尽管如此
I, nevertheless,
我还是知道我们的士兵有斗志
know the fighting spirit of our men.
我对他们有信心
And I have faith in them.
但我还需要知道
But I also need to know
他们对自己有信心
that they have faith in themselves.
我需要你成为我的山本大将
I need you to be my Admiral Yamamoto.
以他的角度思考  告诉我他的下一步意图
Get in his head. Tell me what he's going to do next.
你的第一个任务
Your first assignment...
就是我们需要发起进攻
we need to throw a punch.
不止是为了提振士气
Not just for morale,
还要让日本人知道挨打是什么感受
but so the Japanese know what it feels like to be hit.
我要派哈尔西去攻击马绍尔群岛
I'm sending Halsey to attack the Marshall Islands.
但我需要知道
But I need to know
他们不会遭受埋伏
that they're not walking into a trap.
1942年2月1日
马绍尔群岛
目标是莱岛
The target is Roi Island.
我们的潜艇报告那里存在船只航行
Our submarines have reported shipping traffic
并有一个军用机场
and one military airfield.
我们不清楚目标的情况
We don't know what we're facing,
所以能打多狠打多狠  然后撤离
so hit 'em as hard as possible and then get the hell out.
那敌军航母呢
So what about the enemy carrier?
情报称他们在三千多公里之外
Intelligence says they're 2,000 miles away.
你是说之前那群
You mean the same group of geniuses
不知道小日本要袭击珍珠港的天才吗
who didn't know the Japs were gunning for Pearl?
如我所说
Like I said,
做好万全准备
be prepared for anything.
早起的鸟儿有虫吃  先生们
The early bird catches the worm, gentlemen.
我们要趁小日本还没起床
We're gonna hit that anchorage
袭击那片锚泊地
before the Japs have even rolled out of bed.
他的口水都把鞋子洗干净了
Looks like he spit polished his shoes.
伙计们  我们要全身而退
Hey, guys, let's get home in one piece.
不用担心
Oh, don't you worry.
计划是什么  长官
What's the plan, sir?
其他中队会先发起攻击
The other squadrons will strike first.
然后我们进场  清理掉剩下的目标
Then we go in and clean up the remaining targets.
小日本那时会对我们有所防备
Japs will know we're coming.
要是我们被击落怎么办
What happens if we get shot down?
听着  我不会沦为战俘的
Look, I'm not gonna end up as a POW.
你也不会
And neither are you.
我看到了一个大型目标
I've got a large target in my sight.
飞到足够接近的位置来提高命中率
Get close enough to make it count.
开始行动  伙计们  发射鱼雷
Start your runs, boys. Engage torpedoes.
看起来进攻莱岛的部队捅了马蜂窝
Looks like our boys on Roi poked a hornet's nest.
我们遇到了一个问题
We got a problem.
我在塔罗亚岛发现了第二个敌军机场
I got eyes on a second enemy airfield on Taroa Island.
目测大概有三十架轰炸机  并有重型战斗机掩护
I'm counting maybe 30 bombers and heavy fighter cover.
听到了吗  伙计们
You hear that, boys?
如果我们不摧毁那个机场
If we don't knock out that airfield,
他们会袭击企业号
they'll go after Enterprise.
这次战斗结束后  我还希望有能降落的地方
And I want a place to land when this is over.
敌军战斗机  十一点钟方向
Enemy fighters, 11 o'clock!
遭遇敌机  开始行动
We got company. Start your runs!
九百米
3,000!
六百一
2,000!
五百八
1,900!
五百五
1,800!
四百九
1,600!
帮我甩掉这些混蛋  默里
Get those bastards off me, Murray!
我们离开这里  默里
Let's get out of here, Murray.
我们摧毁了大部分轰炸机  但还剩一些
We got most of the bombers, but not all of them.
看起来他们差点把你打下来
Looks like they almost got you.
是啊  但弹药不够
Yeah, not enough lead.
怎么  刺激过头了吗
What, too much excitement for ya?
我可不想赢得勋章
I'm not looking to win a medal.
意指战死
知道吗  海军会让你赔这架飞机的
You know, the Navy's gonna make you pay for this aircraft.
你们情况怎么样
How'd you boys do?
霍平阵亡了
We lost Hopping.
他俯冲后没能拉起来
He never pulled out of his dive.
情况不妙
That can't be good.
双引擎轰炸机  五点钟方向
Twin-engine bombers, five o'clock.
这些该死的炮手
Goddamn gunners.
他们不知道得打提前量吗
Don't they know they gotta lead those planes?
-右标准舵  -防备
- Right standard rudder. - Brace!
防备冲击
Brace for impact!
他在干什么
What the hell is he doing?
他把自己变成了炸弹
He's turning himself into a bomb.
来啊  来啊
Come on! Come on!
牛逼  布鲁诺
Damn, Bruno.
他们花钱不就是雇我们杀小日本的吗
Aren't they paying us to kill Japs?
哈尔西司令想见你
Admiral Halsey wants to see you.
这是我见过最勇敢的行为
That's the bravest damn thing I think I've ever seen.
你叫什么  孩子
What's your name, son?
布鲁诺·盖多  长官
Bruno Gaido, sir.
三等航空机械师
Aviation Machinist's Mate, Third Class.
布鲁诺  你现在是一等航空机械师了
Well, Bruno, you are now an Aviation Machinist's Mate, First Class.
给舰队发信号
Signal the fleet.
告诉他们是时候和哈尔西一起赶路了
Tell 'em it's time to haul ass with Halsey.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你听到了  给舰队发信号
You heard the man. Signal the fleet.
夏威夷  檀香山
军官俱乐部
美国海军乐队
西弗吉尼亚州号
晚七点
今晚客串嘉宾
詹妮弗·达琳
你确定你今晚想要
Are you really sure you want your wife
你妻子为你做僚机吗
flying wingman for you tonight?
没人跟我说今晚美军慰问协会的姑娘也会来
Yeah, nobody told me there'd be USO girls here tonight.
我给我们找了个位子
I got us a table.
韦德  你见过安吗
Wade, have you met Ann?
我是韦德·麦克拉斯基
Wade McClusky.
我和你丈夫一起执行飞行任务
I fly with your husband.
你想喝一杯吗
Hey, uh, you want a drink?
你想让我跳舞的话  我就喝
I do, if you want me to dance.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你们结婚多久了
How long have you been married?
久到足以了解我丈夫的才能
Long enough to know my husband's talents.
为什么他不负责指挥中队
Why isn't he commanding a squadron?
我说了不算
I don't make those decisions.
-麻烦给我两杯迈泰  -是  长官
- Two Mai Tai, please. - Yes, sir.
我明白在战争之前
I understand before the war,
升官靠的是政治手腕  但现在呢
when it was about politics, but now?
我告诉你了  她不是个省油的灯
I told you she was a firecracker.
我得说
I have to say,
我经常会想什么样的女人会嫁给迪克·贝斯特
I often wondered what kind of woman would marry Dick Best...
你没让我失望
and, well, you have not disappointed.
迪克·贝斯特
Dick Best.
-你好  莱顿  -你好
- Hey, Layton. - Hey.
马绍尔群岛的战况如何
How was the Marshall Islands?
我们初试身手
Yeah, we got our feet wet.
你一直在关注我吗
You keeping tabs on me?
我可是舰队情报部的
Ah, I'm with Fleet Intelligence.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
在珍珠港事件之后  我们需要你这样的聪明人
Yeah, we're gonna need someone as smart as you after Pearl.
你会把那些家伙调教好吗
You gonna straighten those boys out?
我尽力
I'll do my best.
您的迈泰  长官
Your Mai Tai, sir.
我支持你
Well, I'm rooting for you.
-替我跟你妻子问好  -你也是
- Hey, say hi to the wife. - You as well.
直说吧
Just be straight with me.
我还漏了什么
What am I missing?
我们每次驾驶战机上天
Every time we go up in one of those planes,
都有可能回不来
there's a chance we won't come back.
追随一个不清楚这一点的人很难
Now, it's hard to follow a man who doesn't know that.
更糟的是...
Or even worse...
他不在乎这一点
doesn't care.
我们跳舞吧
Let's dance.
好
Okay.
失陪
Excuse me.
All Or Nothing At All
♪ 全部或者全不 ♪
♪ All or nothing at all ♪
♪ 不完整的爱 ♪
♪ Half a love ♪
♪ 从未吸引我 ♪
♪ never appealed to me ♪
♪ 如果你的心永远不向我屈服 ♪
♪ If your heart never could yield to me ♪
♪ 那我宁可一无所获 ♪
♪ Then I'd rather have nothing at all ♪
去睡觉吧
Come to bed.
欢迎登上企业号
Welcome aboard Enterprise.
你们接替的是出色的军人
You're replacing good men.
比我和海军希望的要早得多  但是...
Much earlier than me or the Navy wanted, but...
这就是我们现在面临的处境
Well, that's the hand we've been dealt.
现在轮到你们了
Now, you're going in the rotation,
身为中队的二把手  我的职责是
and as XO, it's my job to make sure
确保你们比一桶口水用处大点
you're worth more than a bucket of warm spit.
小日本正等着我们
The Japs are waiting for us,
我们需要能够独当一面的飞行员
so we need pilots who can hold their own.
你得来看看这个
You gotta see this.
1942年4月18日
日本以东1046公里处
陆军的飞机来航母上做什么
What the hell are army planes doing on a carrier?
布朗宁先生
Well, Mr. Browning,
那些轰炸机的指挥官
the commander of those bombers?
詹姆斯·杜立特中校
Lieutenant Colonel James Doolittle.
可能是世界上最棒的飞行员
Maybe the best pilot in the world.
他准备让他的飞机从大黄蜂号起飞
And he intends to launch his planes off the Hornet,
空袭东京  然后在中国的非日占区降落
strike Tokyo, and then land in Free China.
舰长
Captain?
八十公里外发现敌军警戒舰艇
Enemy pickets 50 miles out.
他们会暴露我们的行踪
They're gonna blow our cover.
我们把杜立特多送出一公里
Every mile we get Doolittle closer to Japan,
就能让他多一点燃油飞离日本
is fuel he can use to get the hell out of there.
但我不会拿这些航母冒险
But I'm not gonna risk these carriers.
我们要怎么告知杜立特
What do we tell Doolittle?
告知实情
The truth.
我们得到了起飞的命令
We got the order to launch.
我们距离还有多远
How far out are we?
太远了
Too far.
我们可能最后得在中国东海迫降
We'll probably end up ditching in the East China Sea.
但如果我们轰炸了东京
But if we bomb Tokyo,
我们就会成为日本历史上
we'll be the first enemy in Japan's history
第一个打到他们本土的敌人
to hit their home territory.
如果你们谁想退出
If any of you want to bow out,
就现在说出来
now's your chance.
我们都想参与行动  长官
We all wanna fly, sir.
登上飞机
Man your planes.
大家中国再会
I'll see you all in China.
他们没法起飞
They can't take off.
载重那么大肯定没法起飞
Certainly not with a load.
而且他们肯定没法降落
And they sure as hell can't land.
赌十块他们连甲板都离开不了
Ten bucks says they don't make it off the deck.
好  我赌
Yeah, I'll take that bet.
美国海军鹦鹉螺号潜艇
珍珠港  潜艇基地
大家好
Hello, everyone.
这里是东京广播电台
This is Radio Tokyo,
正在报道美军在菲律宾的溃败
talking about the collapse of American forces in the Philippines.
我们光荣的大日本皇军已经俘获了几千名...
Our glorious Japanese forces have captured thousands...
晚上好  先生们
Evening, gents.
怎么了  上校
What's going on, Captain?
那声音听着像防空警报
Those sound like air raid sirens to me.
天皇陛下  我们必须带您去避难所
天皇陛下  这边走
Heavenly sovereign, this way.
投弹完毕  长官
Bombs away, sir.
我们赶紧离开这里
Let's get out of here.
战争计划
太平洋舰队文件
机密
-别  -我先扣押了
- No. - Taking these hostage.
给我半个小时就行
Just half an hour.
美国真的要靠
Does America winning the war
埃德温·莱顿工作到死才能赢得这场战争吗
really depend on Edwin Layton working himself to death?
我们的军队今天轰炸了东京
Some of our boys bombed Tokyo today.
他们应该在中国的非日占区降落
They were supposed to land in Free China.
但是他们可能会不够油
But they're probably gonna run out of fuel
只能在中国海上迫降
and have to ditch in the China Sea.
如果他们碰巧降落在了
If, by some miracle, they actually make it
中国的日占区
into Japanese occupied territory,
就会遭受酷刑并被处决
they'll be tortured and executed.
你能做什么
What can you do?
几乎什么都做不了
Most likely nothing.
但我们不能再因为我的情报不够充分
But we're not gonna lose any more men
而失去任何士兵了
because I didn't dig deep enough.
我去帮你做个三明治
I'll fix you a sandwich.
我一直在反复计算
I keep recalculating,
但考虑到现在稳定的顺风...
but with this steady tailwind...
你觉得我们现在在陆地上空吗
You think we're over land?
可能是的
Yeah. Maybe.
只有一种方法能得知答案
Only one way to find out.
各位  我们要跳伞了
Everyone. We gotta bail out.
自动驾驶
我不知道我们是在中国还是日本领土上空
I don't know if we're over Chinese or Jap territory.
所以小心点
So, watch yourselves.
我们衢州见
I'll see you all in Quzhou.
下一个是你  波特
You're next, Potter.
柱岛锚泊地
日本  广岛湾
长官
别烦我
你必须从船舱里出来
我们把天皇的性命置于险境
就是几个炸弹而已
我们发誓过要为我们的祖国构筑不可逾越的防线
现在所有人都认同你对于美军航母的看法
我们必须摧毁它们
东条英机说我们必须完成在珊瑚海的行动
但之后我们可以把重心转移到中途岛
那我们就有工作要做了
你们这里有火车站...
You have a train station...
中国  浙江
日本占领区
有烟冒出来  是火车吗
Smoke comes out. Train?
我是你们的朋友
I'm a friend.
美国人  我是友军
American. I'm an ally.
我要去衢州
I need to get to Quzhou.
衢州
Quzhou.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
我叫朱学三
My name is Zhu Xuesan.
我是教书的
School teacher.
你是美国人吗
You are American?
是美国人  我昨天轰炸了日本
American. I bombed Japan yesterday.
那飞机在哪里
Where... Where's the plane?
飞机坠毁了
It crashed.
我昨晚跳伞了  然后降落在海上了
I bailed out and landed in the water last night.
那降落伞呢
Where's, uh, para... parachute?
我留在岸边了
I left it at the shore.
你可以问他们
Ask them.
我半夜敲过他们的门
I knocked on their door in the middle of the night.
他说你撒谎
He say you lie.
他想要你的枪
He want your gun.
我是美军军官
I'm an American officer.
我要留着我的枪
I keep my gun.
你轰炸了日本
You bomb Japan?
没错
I sure did.
-欢迎  欢迎  -你好
- Welcome. Welcome. - Hi.
我要去衢州
I need to get to Quzhou.
-去衢州  -衢州
- To Quzhou. - Quzhou.
-衢州  -衢州
- Quzhou. - Quzhou.
好
Yeah.
日本人正在派航母
The Japanese are sending their carriers
赶往珊瑚海
into the Coral Sea.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
他们想切断我们与澳大利亚之间的生命线
They're trying to break our lifeline with Australia.
发一条加密信息给哈尔西司令
Send a secure message to Admiral Halsey.
我想让企业号
I want Enterprise to join
跟约克城号和列克星敦号一起参与珊瑚海之战
Yorktown and Lexington in the Coral Sea.
告诉哈尔西越快越好
And tell Halsey time is a factor.
还要一件事
There's something else.
事情总是一件接一件
There always is.
我听了一种推测
I heard a theory.
什么样的推测
What kind of theory?
我的一个部下认为
According to one of my officers,
珊瑚海只是热身
Coral Sea is just a warm-up.
他觉得日军有更大的企图
He thinks that the Japanese are planning something bigger.
比这次要大得多
Much bigger.
他为什么会这么想
What makes him think that?
因为我们截获的一些电报片段
Little bits and pieces that we've intercepted.
关于一艘战列舰还没有为即将到来的行动
A message about a battleship not being ready
做好准备的消息
for an upcoming operation.
对阿留申群岛地图的请求
Request for maps of the Aleutian Islands.
目标是什么
What's the target?
我们还不知道
We don't know yet.
你信任你这个部下吗
Do you trust this officer?
他是我认识的最聪明的人
He's the most brilliant man I know.
那就让他弄清楚
Well, have him figure it out.
总是没火柴
Always no match.
你留着吧
Keep it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这里没有军事设施
There are no installations here.
他们的目标是什么
What's their target?
人就是他们的目标
People are target.
人
People.
而我们让事情变得更糟了
And we just made it worse.
我得走了
I have to go.
我的家人
My family.
他们  他们会带你去衢州
They... They take you Quzhou.
帮你找到你的战友
Help find your men.
谢谢你
Thank you.
所做的一切
For everything.
1942年5月8日
南太平洋  珊瑚海
晚到了24个小时
24 hours too late.
该死  我们当时要是也在就好了
Damn it. Why couldn't we have been here?
太平洋上只剩我们和大黄蜂号
This leaves us and Hornet as the only carriers
这两艘航母了
in the Pacific.
立正致意
Attention on deck.
我想跟麦克拉斯基和贝斯特谈谈
I wanna talk to McClusky and Best.
稍息
As you were.
天呐
For Christ's sake.
你没事吧  司令
You okay, Admiral?
我起了皮疹
I got this damn rash.
听着  我受够玩弄权术了
Listen up. I'm done playing politics.
海军
The Navy...
见鬼  整个国家都指望着我们
hell, the whole damn country is counting on us.
我得把最优秀的部下都安排在合适的位置上
And I need my best men in the right spots.
所以  麦克拉斯基
So, McClusky,
你现在负责指挥航空大队
you are now in charge of the air group.
我对那些破鱼雷机
I don't have a lick of confidence
一点信心都没有
in those damn torpedoes.
所以  我想让你来开俯冲轰炸机
So, I want you in a dive bomber.
还有  贝斯特
And, Best,
我要把你从二把手升上来
I'm bumping you up from XO.
你现在是第六轰炸机中队的新任中队长
You're the new skipper of Bombing Six.
祝你们好运  孩子们
Good luck, boys.
我猜你这下不得不学开无畏式俯冲轰炸机了
Well, I guess you're gonna have to learn to fly an SBD.
我已经开了很久无畏式了
I've logged plenty of hours in the Dauntless.
但没有朝实战目标俯冲过
Not diving at a live target.
不会太难吧
Can't be that hard.
我是说  你都能做到
I mean, you do it.
你竟敢不遵循我们的战略
How dare you! You're not following our strategy.
南云司令
这样可没法进行军事推演
这些年轻人完全不顾作战理论  我遵循了您的计划
用航母攻击了中途岛
我们已经做好准备  只要珍珠港的美军航母驰援  我们就调头对付他们
但是呢
我的美军航母不是从珍珠港来的
他们在中途岛东北面待命
当南云司令的飞机轰炸中途岛时  我击沉了他的三艘航母
这步是不可能的  因为美国人不会知道我们要来
重新推演一次
但这次美国航母必须从珍珠港来
我刚跟华盛顿通完电话
So, I just got off the phone with Washington,
他们的情报人员
and their intelligence guys
认为你对这次重大行动判断有误
think you're wrong about this big operation.
他们认为日军会把航母
They think that the Japs are sending their carriers
调回珊瑚海
back into the Coral Sea.
是的  他们还命令我让企业号镇守在那
Yeah, and they've ordered me to keep Enterprise down there.
这是个错误
That's a mistake.
华盛顿从一个错误的假设出发
Washington is starting from a faulty assumption
然后去寻找证据印证它
and looking for evidence to corroborate it.
那日军真正的目标是什么
So, what's the Japs' real target?
我们认为是中途岛
We believe it's Midway.
他们把我们那里的基地视作朝夏威夷
They see our base there as a step towards Hawaii
以及最终朝西海岸进军的跳板
and eventually the West Coast.
什么时候
When?
几周后
In a few weeks.
我想是时候拜访一下
I think it's time to pay a visit
你在夏威夷信号情报站的朋友了
to your friends in Station HYPO.
马特  把车开过来
Matt, bring the car around.
我得提醒您  长官  破译人员很另类
I have to warn you, sir, codebreakers are a rare breed.
罗彻福特的行事风格尤其...
Rochefort's way of doing things is especially...
特别
particular.
只要情报准确  就算他
I don't care if he consults coffee grounds
边跳布吉舞边用咖啡渣占卜
while doing the boogie-woogie
我都没意见
as long as the intel is good.
立正致意
Attention on deck.
继续吧  先生们
Carry on, gentlemen.
罗彻福特在哪
Where's Rochefort?
跟我来吧  长官
If you'll follow me, sir.
我都不知道海军
Didn't realize that the Navy
居然有这么多受过训练的破译人员
had so many trained codebreakers.
并没有
We don't.
这些人大都来自加利福尼亚号上的乐队
Most of these men were in the band on the California.
但由于现在没什么人听乐队了
But since we don't have much use for bands these days,
罗彻福特觉得他们的音乐才能
Rochefort thought that their musical abilities
可能会使他们成为
might make them naturals
解开密码韵律的天才
at breaking the rhythms of ciphers.
抱歉  上将
Sorry, Admiral, it, uh,
地下有点冷
gets cold down here in the dungeon.
听说你很出色
I'm told you're brilliant.
谁都知道莱顿少校
Well, Lieutenant Commander Layton
喜欢夸大其词
has been known to exaggerate.
希望他没有
I hope not.
他非常肯定地告诉我
He told me he's absolutely certain
日军会袭击中途岛
the Japs are gonna hit Midway
我需要知道
and I need to know
我能否相信他
whether or not I can believe him.
如果你不相信他
Well, if you don't believe him,
我们就都要说日语了
we'll all be speaking Japanese.
或者  我们更有可能死掉
Or, most likely, we'll be dead.
让我看看你们怎么做的
Show me how this works.
就像观光那样
You mean, like a tour?
没错
Exactly.
就像观光
Like a tour.
这是破译的起点
So, this is where it starts.
我们拦截大约60%的
We intercept roughly 60%
日军加密无线电通信
of secure Japanese radio traffic
并破解了他们足够的代码
and we've cracked enough of their code
来译出这些信息的40%
to be able to break about 40% of those messages.
所以我们能读到他们
So, we're able to read about a quarter
大约四分之一的加密通信
of their secure communications?
不  不是的
No, not exactly.
这是我们破译的
Here's some of our, uh,
一些信息
cracked messages.
看起来像天书
It's gibberish to me.
是的  但如果你看得足够多...
Yes, but if you read enough of it...
罗彻福特有拼接碎片的天赋
Rochefort has a gift for assembling the fragments.
他能想起两个月前的一条信息
He can recall a message from two months ago,
接入今天拦截的消息
and plug it into today's intercept.
解释一下你和华盛顿的意见分歧
Explain the disagreement with Washington.
我们都能获取同样的原始信息
Well, we all have access to the same raw information,
但这里  是我们各行其是的环节
but, uh, over here, is where our paths diverge.
翻译和分析
Translation and analysis.
现在  华盛顿和我们都认同
Now, Washington agrees with us
日本会袭击一个代号为AF的主要目标
that Japs are gonna attack a major target codenamed AF.
但华盛顿认为AF
But Washington believes that AF
位于南太平洋
is located in the South Pacific,
因而命令你让企业号镇守在那
which is why they ordered you to keep Enterprise down there.
你有直接证据证明他们是错的吗
Do you have any direct proof that they're wrong?
直接证据  没有  但是...
Direct proof? No, but...
长官
Sir.
想象一下您要举办一场婚礼
Imagine that you're throwing a wedding.
也许我从没见过邀请函
And maybe I've never seen the invitation,
但我听承办商说
but I hear from the caterers
他们某天有场活动
that they have an event on a certain date.
搞花卉的要买光整个岛上
The flower guy is buying up all the roses
所有的玫瑰
on the island.
最好的乐队被预订了
The best band is booked.
这就是信号情报所能提供的
That's what signal intelligence can give you.
线索
Clues.
而不是一个确凿的答案
Not a definitive answer.
长官  珍珠港事件后  您让我坚定自己的想法
Sir? After Pearl, you told me to stick to my guns.
我向您发誓  乔是对的
I swear to you, Joe's right about this.
我通常不倾向于
I'm not generally predisposed
相信一帮吹大号的
to trust a bunch of tuba players
和他们穿毛绒拖鞋的领导
led by a man wearing fuzzy slippers.
但是...
But...
我会想办法把企业号调回这里来
I'll figure a way to get the Enterprise back here.
同时  你们需要说服华盛顿
Meantime, you gentlemen need to convince Washington
日军真正的目标是中途岛
that the Japs' real target is Midway.
怎么说服  长官
How, sir?
华盛顿可没有听从我们的习惯
Washington doesn't exactly have a habit of listening to us.
我相信你们会想到对策的
Well, I'm sure you'll think of something.
止咳糖浆  感冒滴鼻剂
进来
Come in.
珍珠港来的机密消息
An eyes-only message from Pearl.
尼米兹
Nimitz.
他想让我们被发现
He wants us to be spotted.
因为如果日军看见我们
Because if the Japs see us,
我们就能违反华盛顿的长期命令
we can break our standing orders with Washington
然后回珍珠港
and return to Pearl.
我们从没收到过这条消息
We never received this message.
长官  上将找您
Sir? The admiral needs you.
好
Okay.
对  好
Yeah. Okay.
随时通知我
Well, keep me informed.
华盛顿打来的
That was Washington.
他们拦截了几条日军信息
They've intercepted several Japanese messages
称他们下一个袭击目标
claiming that the target of their upcoming attack
没有淡水了
is out of fresh water.
有意思  长官
Interesting, sir.
我听说中途岛不小心发出
I heard that Midway accidentally sent out
一条未加密的信息
an unencrypted transmission
说他们的淡水处理设备坏了
that their water plant was broken.
那他们的设备真的坏了吗
And is their water plant broken?
据我所知没有  长官
Not that I know of, sir.
但那证明了中途岛就是AF
But that proves Midway is AF.
好  告诉你的部下罗彻福特
Okay, tell your man, Rochefort
现在所有人都认同
that everyone now agrees
他要举行婚礼的地点
on where his wedding is gonna be held.
我们只需要知道要来多少客人
We just need to know how many guests are coming
以及他们计划到达的时间
and when they plan to arrive.
中途岛
1942年5月28日
麦克  我想我们找到拍摄地点了
Mack, I think we found the spot.
说不好  福特先生
Can't say, Mr. Ford,
我曾帮好莱坞一位当红导演
that I've ever helped a big-time Hollywood director
做过采景
scout for a movie before.
你打算在这么个鸟不拉屎的地方
What kind of film you planning to make
拍什么样的电影啊
in a godforsaken place like this?
我在海军的朋友说
Friend of mine in the Navy said
我也许能在这里找到真正的场面
that I might be able to find some real action here.
我觉得我被骗了
I think I've been hoodwinked.
我说不好  长官
I don't know, sir.
从我们在这座小岛上设防的情况来看
From the way we've been fortifying this little island,
你朋友的情报还真靠谱
I'd say your friend has some good intel.
立正致意
Attention on deck.
真好玩
Very funny.
快给我坐下吧
Sit the hell down.
长话短说
I'm gonna keep this short.
我知道你们中有些人认为
I know some of you thought
我是个难应付的二把手  但是...
I was a pain in the ass as XO but...
但是更难应付的还在后面
Well, that's about to get worse.
我们要回到珍珠港补给
We're headed back to Pearl to resupply,
这可能意味着
and it's probably because something big
有大事要发生了
is coming down the pipe.
因此我们的侦察频率得加倍
I'm therefore doubling our scouting flights
我希望你们一有机会
and I expect you to practice diving runs
就练习俯冲
whenever you get a chance.
面对日军时
Don't be the man
别做那个拖中队后腿的人
who lets down the squadron when we finally face the Japs.
解散
Dismissed.
我能跟您谈谈吗  长官
Can I talk to you, sir?
我不知道我能否做到  长官
I don't know if I can do this, sir.
我曾认为自己是个优秀的飞行员
I thought I was a good pilot,
但我对自己失去了信心
but I've lost my confidence.
你为什么要当飞行员
Why did you become a pilot?
你父亲希望你成为军官  对吧
Your dad wanted you to be an officer, huh?
其实我父亲不怎么尊重军官
Actually, my dad didn't have much respect for officers.
他说大多数军官都是蠢货
Said that most of them didn't know their ass from their elbow.
我父亲是个顽固的混蛋
You know, my dad was a tough son of a bitch.
你知道我是怎么得到他的尊重的吗
You know how I got his respect?
我一直坚守战场
By always staying in the fight.
我也希望有闲暇
I wish I had the luxury
顾及你的自信心
of worrying about your confidence,
但我们正缺飞行员
but we're short on pilots,
所以你得咬咬牙
so, you gotta suck it up.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
等等
Wait.
从现在起  你就是我的僚机了
From now on, you're my wingman.
我会照应你的
I'll be lookin' out for you.
去换好衣服  准备侦察吧
Now go suit up for a scouting flight.
告诉我
Tell me.
你的秘诀是什么
What's your secret?
我的秘诀
My secret?
他想知道你为什么无忧无虑
He wants to know why nothing bothers you.
我叔叔曾是帝国大厦的一名焊工
My uncle was a welder on the Empire State Building.
他在三百米高空上的
He'd walk on a beam,
钢梁上走动  不系安全绳
1,000 feet up in the sky, no ropes, nothing.
大家都觉得他疯了
And everyone thought he was crazy,
但于他而言  他只是在做分内之事
but to him, he was just doing a job.
后来的一个周日  他从教堂回家
And one Sunday, he's walking home from church.
在离家只有一个街区时
He's a block away from his house,
一辆的士冲上了人行道
when a cab jumps over the curb,
像碾死一只虫子那样撞死了他
splatters him like a bug.
你无从知晓自己的结局
You never know what's gonna get you.
所以何必为之烦忧呢
So, why worry about it?
出发吧
Hey. Let's go.
这只是简单的侦察任务
Simple scouting mission.
回来的路上  我们练习俯冲  好吗
On the way home, we'll practice the dive, you got it?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
这次我们的幅度会更大
We'll be going deeper this time,
所以在最低点时别太快拉起
so don't pull up too fast on the bottom
否则你会晕过去的
or you'll black out.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
航母的航速太慢了
The ship's moving too slow.
中止  中止起飞
Abort! Abort takeoff!
航速太慢了
The ship's too slow!
无法产生起飞所需的风速
We're not generating enough wind for launch.
不  停下  停下
No, stop! Stop!
飞机落水
Plane in water.
右转舵  该死
Turn starboard, God damn it!
右转舵
Turn starboard.
1942年5月29日
珍珠港
我猜你也不喜欢系上领口
Guess you don't like the chokers either.
我光是扣上扣子就弄得油腻腻了
I'd get grease on that thing just trying to button it up.
让我看起来像个服务生一样
Makes me look like a damn waiter.
没人会把你错认成服务生的
Nobody would ever confuse you for a waiter.
你看起来很糟糕  比尔
You look like hell, Bill.
我没事
I'm fine.
疲倦而已
Tired.
舰上的每个人都很疲倦
Every man on the ship's tired.
我们已经连轴转六个月了
We've been out six months without a break.
你现在的鬼样子和疲倦
There's a big difference
还是有很大区别的
between tired and whatever the hell you are.
你得去陆地上的医院
You're going ashore to the hospital.
你觉得这像是战伤吗
Does this look like a battle wound to you?
只是皮疹而已
It's a damn rash.
如果他们的司令
Now, what are my men gonna think
决定跑去休假
when their admiral up and decides
我的部下会怎么想
he needs a vacation?
这是命令  比尔
It's a direct order, Bill.
我们不断损兵折将
And we keep losing men.
甚至还没和日军交火
It's not even the Japs.
赫尔曼在起飞时坠机了
Herman crashed on takeoff.
汤姆·杜尔金在巡逻时失踪了
Tom Durkin disappeared on patrol.
还有那个孩子
And there's this other kid...
威利·韦斯特
Willie West.
他在出发前就觉得自己做不到
He didn't think he could cut it.
我以为那只是正常的紧张
I figured it was just the usual jitters.
我想要保护他
I take him under my wing.
昨天我给他母亲写了封信
I wrote a letter to his mother yesterday
告诉她我没能保护好他
telling her I failed him.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
他应该感到害怕
He was right to be scared.
大家都知道大战降临
Everybody knows something big is coming.
我们要用几十架飞机
We're talking about a couple dozen planes
对抗日军的整支舰队
against the whole Japanese fleet.
如果我们输了  他们就会称霸太平洋
And if we lose, they own the Pacific,
随后袭击西海岸
and they raid the West Coast.
西雅图  旧金山  洛杉矶
Seattle, San Francisco, Los Angeles...
都将陷入战火
will burn.
而且这次战争将持续十年之久
And this damn war will last a decade.
我从未见过你如此担忧
I've never seen you this worried before.
如果只是我和我的飞机  我从不担忧
I never had to worry when it was just me and my plane...
但是这次不一样  安  我得领导这些士兵
but, Ann, it's different now. I have to lead these men.
我该跟他们说什么
What do I say to them?
只要
Just...
坦诚就好
be honest.
让他们看见我所看见的
And let them see what I can see.
他们就会追随你到天涯海角  迪克·贝斯特
They'll follow you anywhere, Dick Best.
美国海军约克城号
珍珠港  干船坞
长官  约克城号被一枚230公斤的炸弹击中
Sir, the Yorktown was hit by a 500-pound bomb.
我们需要至少两周时间来修复
We need at least two weeks for repairs.
不行
Not acceptable.
我们初步预测要在西雅图的干船坞停靠三个月
Our initial estimate was three months in dry dock in Seattle.
我需要这艘航母
I need this ship.
我不管你用什么材料修补甲板
I don't care if you need to patch the deck with plywood.
约克城号72小时后必须起航
Yorktown sails in 72 hours.
哈尔西暂时离开了
Halsey is out.
他由于皮疹住进了医院
He's in the hospital with shingles.
因此我将第十六特混舰队的指挥权
So I've given command of Task Force 16
交给斯普鲁恩斯少将
to Admiral Spruance.
我们要设置陷阱
We're setting a trap.
我们的航母将在
Our carriers will lie in wait
中途岛的东北方向待命
northeast of Midway.
我们在这里设下了一条潜艇警戒线
Now, we have set up a picket line of submarines here.
至于中途岛
As for Midway itself,
我们已经在跑道上塞满了所有能抽出的飞机了
we have crammed every plane we can spare onto that runway.
不过这一次  如果我们运气好
But this time, if we're lucky,
我们将打日军一个措手不及
surprise will be on our side.
莱顿  关于日军方位的估算
Layton, how reliable are these estimates
有多准确
of the Japanese positions?
这是我们根据现有情报
They represent our best guess,
做出的最佳推测
based on the intelligence that we have.
我不能根据你的推测来制定作战计划
I can't plan around your guess.
我知道我们的要求有些苛刻
I understand that we're asking the impossible,
但你得具体一点
but we need you to be specific.
日军将于6月4日清晨
The Japanese will attack on the morning of June 4th
从西北方向来袭  方位325度
from the northwest, at a bearing of 325 degrees.
在离中途岛280公里处被我们发现
They will be sighted 175 miles from Midway
时间为当地时间7点
at 0700 local time.
我相信莱顿及其团队
I trust Layton and his team.
制定相应的作战计划
Make your plans accordingly.
解散
Dismissed.
清空甲板
Clear the deck.
珍珠港飞来的第六鱼雷机中队即将降落
Torpedo Squadron Six coming in from Pearl.
清空甲板
Clear the deck.
珍珠港飞来的第六鱼雷机中队即将降落
Torpedo Squadron Six coming in from Pearl.
起落架
降落襟翼
他出问题了
He's in trouble.
该死
Shit.
我们需要救援队
We need a rescue team!
-小心  小心  -小心  大家小心
- Easy. Easy. Easy. - Easy, boys. Easy.
把他扶过来
Get him over.
抬上来  一  二  三
Hand him off. One, two, three.
小心  上尉
Easy, Lieutenant.
你的背部感觉如何  上尉
How's your back doing, Lieutenant?
感觉像是有人往我背上砸了台拖拉机
It feels like someone dropped a tractor on it.
这就是你的中队要面对的吗
So, that's what your squadrons are up against?
250架护航机
侵略舰队
四艘航母
Four carriers.
大约250架飞机
Approximately 250 aircraft,
还有世界上最大的战列舰
plus the biggest battleship in the world.
没错  更不用说小日本是不可战胜的了
Yeah, not to mention the Japs are unbeatable.
我们把那些混蛋打个措手不及
We've got the drop on the bastards.
利用好这一点
Make it count.
林赛怎么样了
How's Lindsey?
情况不妙  长官
Not good, sir.
你相信这些情报吗
Do you trust the intelligence?
我正在努力说服自己
I'm trying.
因为我们对此冒着很大的风险
Because we're betting a hell of a lot on this hand.
没错
Yeah.
我不敢相信自己能说出这样的话  但是...
I can't believe I'm saying this, but, uh...
我更喜欢你自以为是的样子
I liked you better when you were cocky.
你不用担心我
Hey, you don't have to worry about me.
真的不用吗
Oh, really?
你一直在为那个孩子的坠海而自责
You've been blaming yourself for that kid who went down.
我该怎样补偿
How do I make it right?
确保你的部下为明天做好准备
Make sure your men are ready for tomorrow.
尽可能地让大家平安归来
And you bring back as many of 'em as you can.
发现舰只
Ship sighted.
是约克城号
It's the Yorktown!
它是怎么及时开出干船坞的
How the hell did she get out of dry dock in time?
我不清楚
I don't know.
我想每场战役都需要奇迹吧
I guess every battle needs a miracle.
这个沙盘上的每个位置你都记得一清二楚  莱顿
You've memorized every position on that board, Layton.
回家吧
Go home.
我打算在这里过夜  长官
I think I'm going to spend the night here, sir,
以防出现什么情况
just in case anything comes up.
你妻子不介意吗
Your wife doesn't mind?
她知道我们这一行是怎样的
Well, she knows the drill.
我妻子也知道
My wife knows the drill, too,
但她还是会介意
but she still minds.
等战争结束了
And when the war's over,
我会用余生来补偿她
I plan on spending the rest of my life making it up to her.
好好休息吧
Get some rest.
晚安
Good night.
1942年6月4日
他们起飞了全部飞行中队
They've scrambled all the squadrons.
雷达肯定有所发现
Radar must've picked up something.
很好  麦奇  这样很好
That's great, Mikey, that's great.
下次把号角抬高一点  好吗
Next time, get the horn up a little higher, all right?
-好的  先生  -高一点  很好
- All right, sir. - A little higher. Good.
好了  把旗子降下来  我们再来一遍
All right. Lower the flag, we're going again.
都吃点东西吧
Get something in your stomachs.
今天会很漫长
It's gonna be a long day.
我不想说些冠冕堂皇的话
I'm not gonna sugarcoat it, boys.
大家都觉得我们没法跟日军较量
Nobody thinks we can go toe-to-toe with the Japanese.
觉得正常情况我们打不过他们
Not in a fair fight.
今天  我们完全不被看好
Today, we're gonna be big underdogs.
我呢
Me?
我觉得这个房间里的人敢在天上跟任何人斗
I think the men in this room can fly with anyone.
可能这是因为我是个自以为是的混蛋
Maybe that's 'cause I'm a cocky son of a bitch.
但也因为我见识过你们的能力
But it's also because I've seen what you can do.
你们都准备好了
You're ready for this.
我们要把他们打得屁滚尿流
We're gonna give 'em a shellackin'.
上午6点40分
日军航母航空大队
他们来了  日军来袭
They're coming! The Japs are coming!
福特先生  敌机来袭
Mr. Ford, we have incoming aircrafts.
我们得让你进入掩体了
We need to get you to a bunker.
敌机来袭
Incoming aircrafts?
先生  你必须要进掩体了
Sir, you have to take cover, sir.
该死  快上屋顶
Holy shit! To the roof!
福特先生  等等
Mr. Ford, wait!
无意冒犯  先生
With all due respect, sir,
但如果你不进入掩体
there isn't going to be a movie, sir,
-就没法活下来拍电影了  -我可得把这个拍下来
- if we don't get you to cover. - I'm gonna shoot the damn picture.
好了吗  杰基
Got it, Jackie?
漂亮
Beautiful!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
继续拍摄  继续拍摄
Keep shooting. Keep shooting!
中途岛报告遭遇日军空袭
Japanese air attack reported on Midway.
我们有架侦察机刚刚发现了敌军舰队
And one of our scout planes just sighted the enemy fleet.
在哪里发现的
Spotted where?
他报告在方位320度
He reports carriers bearing 320 degrees,
离中途岛西北方向288公里处发现敌军航母
180 miles northwest of Midway.
莱顿  你跟罗彻福特只算差了
Well, Layton, you and Rochefort were only off
五分钟  八公里和五度
five minutes, five miles and five degrees.
我们争取下次做得更好的  长官
Well, we'll endeavor to do better next time, sir.
把敌军方位发给我们的飞行员
Give our pilots the enemy position.
命令他们进行攻击
Tell them to attack.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
上午7点10分
中途岛航空大队
发现敌机  九点钟方向
他们在进行滑翔轰炸
这说明他们都是新手
准备好进行规避机动  新手也有走运的时候
左转舵
右转舵
他在冲向赤城号
他刚才是想直接撞上来吗
美国佬没那么勇敢
他的操纵杆肯定卡住了
那些飞机是从中途岛来的  这说明它仍然是个威胁
我们必须对他们的机场进行第二波攻击
林赛
Lindsey,
你还欠我十美元呢
you still owe me 10 bucks.
你想在我被击落前找我要账
You trying to collect before I get myself shot down?
不是  我知道你准备好了  林赛
Nah, I know you're good for it, Lindsey.
你今天不用飞
You don't have to fly today.
没人会质疑你的勇气
Nobody would doubt your courage.
我会带领我的中队
I will lead my squadron in.
祝你好运  长官
Good luck, sir.
我就在你后面
I'll be right behind you.
我们在日军舰队上空见
I'll meet you at the Japanese fleet.
发现敌军舰队
报告  收到侦察机报告  发现十艘敌军水面舰艇
在东北偏东方向
这不可能
除非这是一个圈套
我们必须摧毁敌军舰队
给准备攻击中途岛的战机重新装配鱼雷和穿甲炸弹
但是长官  我们在换装期间是非常脆弱的
我们的战斗机会保护我们的
是
はい！
上午7点45分
美国海军鹦鹉螺号潜艇
中途岛西北方向402公里处
他们有一艘神通级巡洋舰
They got a Jintsu type cruiser.
距离2286米
Range 2,500 yards.
我才不会在巡洋舰上浪费一发鱼雷
I'm not wasting a torpedo on a cruiser.
航母在哪里
Where are the carriers?
长官  我们得下潜了
Sir, we need to go deep.
全员进入战斗岗位
Man battle stations.
进入战斗岗位  所有人进入岗位
Battle stations. Everybody, in your bunks.
默里
Well, Murray,
就是现在
this is it.
企业号收到中途岛的新侦察报告后
The Enterprise has launched its SBDs
起飞了舰上的各支
and their squadrons of marine dive bombers
无畏式俯冲轰炸机中队
following a new sighting report out of Midway.
我们得爬升高度
We gotta climb higher, boys.
我们要节约燃油
We need to conserve fuel.
上升到4267米
Approaching altitude 14,000 feet.
打开氧气  长官
Release your oxygen, sir.
你还好吗  长官
Are you okay, sir?
我的氧气有问题
It's my oxygen.
肯定混入了什么脏东西
Must've gotten a bad mix.
我们得回去
We have to go back.
这会搞坏你的肺的
It'll tear up your lungs.
我不会让我的中队在没指挥官的情况下去战斗的
I'm not sending the squadron out there without their commander.
它在那里
There she is.
发现一艘航母  距离约3658米
We got a carrier, maybe 4,000 yards.
长官  日军舰只就在我们上方
Sir, the Japs are right on us.
一号和二号发射管准备
Make tubes one and two ready.
一号和二号发射管做好各种准备
Make tubes one and two ready in all respects.
一号和二号发射管准备  收到
Tubes one and two ready, aye.
一号发射管注水
Flood down tube one.
一号发射管注水  收到
Flood down tube one, aye.
发现潜望镜
潜望鏡発見。
长官  发现潜望镜
他们在准备深水炸弹
方位
Bearing.
标记
Mark.
一艘美国潜艇就在我们舰队的正中
相对目标方位
-对准了  -一号发射管
- Matched. - Tube one.
发射
Fire!
命令岚号拖住那艘潜艇
等舰队安全脱离后他们再赶上来
第六轰炸机中队十号  你能看到目标吗
Six Baker 10, do you have visual?
什么都没有
Nothin'.
肯定是侦察报告错了
Must've gotten a bum sighting report.
也可能是他们改变了航线
Or maybe they've changed course.
我们往回搜索一下
Let's do a back search.
又要来一波深水炸弹了
Here they come again.
上午9点38分
林赛的第六鱼雷机中队
发现目标
Target spotted.
很勇敢的士兵
幸运的是他们的飞机太烂了
右满舵
螺旋桨噪音在降低
The screws are fading.
我想他们正在离开  长官
I think they're leaving, sir.
升至潜望深度
Take us to periscope depth.
敌军驱逐舰已经驶回舰队
Enemy destroyer's headed back to her fleet.
我发现了一艘舰只
I've got a ship.
全速航行的日军驱逐舰
Jap destroyer at flank speed.
信不信它在试图
What do you wanna bet
追上他们的航母
she's trying to catch up with the carriers?
长官  我们已经飞行了近两个小时
Sir, we've been up here for almost two hours.
如果我们燃油耗尽
What if we run out of fuel
整个中队就都得迫降海上了
and the whole squadron has to ditch?
那我可能就得去军事监狱洗土豆了
Then I'll probably end up scrubbing potatoes at Leavenworth.
管不了那么多了
To hell with it.
伙计们  跟我来
Follow me, boys.
我希望你是对的  麦克拉斯基
I hope you're right, McClusky.
第六轰炸机中队  跟我来
Bombing Six on me.
上午9点55分
大黄蜂号第八鱼雷机中队
你觉得他们发现我们了吗
Think they've seen us?
如果他们发现了  我们会知道的
When they see us, we'll know.
防备冲击
Brace for impact!
由于遭受持续攻击  我们的轰炸机无法起飞
我们的战斗机不能再沉迷追击了
他们飞得太低了
那些飞机是从一艘航母起飞的
我们必须发起攻击
是
は！
长官  山口司令发来一条消息
建议立即对敌军进行空袭
他以为我不想这么做吗
源田  情况怎么样了
请您稍等
一切准备就绪了吗
我们已经以最快速度在换装了  但是从对地武器换为对海武器需要时间
再给你五分钟
这里简直就是火药桶
见了鬼了
God damn it.
这个牛逼的家伙还真找到日军舰队了
That magnificent son of a bitch actually found them.
好了  伙计们
All right, boys.
第六轰炸机中队  我们先去干掉这第一艘航母
Bombing Six, we've got the first bastard in line.
他们就快准备好了
很好  我们要全力出击  击溃敌军舰队
贝斯特长官  小心
Mr. Best, watch out!
搞什么
What the hell?
麦克拉斯基本该去炸较远的那艘航母
McClusky was supposed to go for the far carrier.
跟紧我
Stay on me.
高度一千二
We at 4,000.
九百
3,000!
炸沉它  快啊
Do it, baby, come on!
炸沉它
Come on!
六百
2,000!
五百五
1,800!
加把劲  迪金森  做你该做的
Come on, Dickinson, do what you're paid to do.
太棒了
Yeah!
快看
苍龙号也遭到攻击
冷静点  你是一名军官
那就只剩下我们和赤城号了
除非那几架飞机来袭击我们
是不是有点孤单  长官
Feeling a little lonely, sir?
真希望我们开来了更多飞机
Wish we'd brought more planes to the party.
你一直都想做个英雄  克罗格
You always wanted to be a hero, Kroeger.
你的机会来了
Now's your chance.
好了  默里
Okay, Murray.
哪怕要坠毁在它的甲板上
We put that carrier out of action
我们也要击毁这艘航母
even if we have to crash on her deck.
高度一千二
4,000!
我们还需要更多时间  长官
我们仍在为轰炸机换装炸弹
九百
3,000!
五百五
1,800!
四百八
1,600!
四百六
1,500!
干得太漂亮了  长官
That was a beauty, sir!
正中甲板
Right on her deck!
后面有敌军战斗机追击吗
Any fighters on our tail?
没有  长官
No, sir.
他们肯定是去追其他人了
They must be chasing someone else.
我们要迫降了
We're going in!
奥弗莱厄蒂和盖多被击落了  长官
O'Flaherty and Gaido are down, sir.
如果你再不击中那些零式战斗机
If you don't hit them damn Zeros,
我们也要坠海了
we're gonna be joining 'em.
您还好吗  长官
Are you okay, sir?
上报我们的位置
Radio our position.
我们得派船出来
We gotta get a ship out here
营救盖多和奥弗莱厄蒂
to pick up Gaido and O'Flaherty.
汽油正在挥发
我们无法使用二氧化碳灭火  我们失去动力了
我们必须撤离了
我必须拯救这艘船
拯救船是船长的职责  您的职责是指挥舰队
您留在这里无法指挥
您想让我们联系斯普鲁恩斯少将吗
Do you want us to contact Admiral Spruance?
不  他不能打破无线电静默
No, he can't break radio silence.
给我的吗
For me?
罗彻福特截获了一条日军讯息
Rochefort intercepted a Japanese signal.
他无法破译正文
He can't translate the body,
但是  看看它的呼叫讯号
but look at the call sign.
是南云司令发出来的
That's from Admiral Nagumo.
但他不是从赤城号
But he's not transmitting from the Akagi.
而是从一艘巡洋舰发出来的
He's transmitting from a cruiser.
南云为什么会离开他的旗舰
Now, why the hell would Nagumo leave his flagship?
下午4点30分
大和号战列舰
中途岛以西965公里处
南云司令发来消息  加贺号  苍龙号和赤城号舰上燃起大火
美国人早就知道我们要来
我们正中他们的圈套
我们仍然可以取胜
但我们必需弄清楚所面对的情况
我们在飞行学校学过关于脱水的知识
They taught us about dehydration in flight school.
皮肤会逐渐开始干裂
Your skin starts to crack,
肝脏也会衰竭
liver fails...
闭嘴吧
Knock it off.
如果没人找到我们怎么办
What if nobody finds us?
那我们就游回珍珠港
We swim back to Pearl.
碰到鲨鱼就惨了
Good luck with sharks.
我们总需要食物吧
We'll need something to eat.
等等  我看见有船
Wait. Wait, I see something.
看起来像是艘驱逐舰
Looks like a destroyer.
美国的还是日本的
American or Jap?
你  交代你们船的动向
You, tell us your ship,
不然就把你扔进海里
or we throw you overboard.
有烟吗
Cigarette?
你知道吗  我在珍珠港有很多朋友
You know, I had a lot of friends at Pearl Harbor.
所以你们去死吧
So how about you go fuck yourself?
我们是舰队里仅存的一支完好的空中编队
日本的命运全靠你们的技术了
天皇希望你们完成自己的职责
默里  吃点东西
Murray, get something to eat.
我打赌我们还得重回战场
I bet we're going back out there.
我们得去上面报告
We have to go upstairs to report.
发生什么了
Hey, what happened?
一架零式战斗机紧追着我
I got strafed by a Zero.
你怎么知道要跟着那艘日本驱逐舰
Hey, how'd you know to follow that Jap destroyer?
凭直觉
I played a hunch.
你的直觉可能帮助我们赢得了这场战役
Well, your hunch might have won us this battle.
但我不得不说
But I gotta tell ya,
我看那很像牛仔脾气那一套
that looked like some cowboy bullshit to me.
如果你不能打败他们  那就加入他们
Well, if you can't beat 'em, join 'em.
约克城号被击中了
Yorktown's hit.
我们还剩哪些部队
What have we got left?
有几架无畏式俯冲轰炸机刚刚返航
Couple of SBDs just returned.
飞行员正要上来报告
The pilots are coming up to report.
敌军舰队有什么新动向
What's the news from the enemy fleet?
三艘航母已被击毁  还剩一艘
Three carriers down. One to go.
我们的航空大队呢
And our air group?
只有三架鱼雷机返航了
Only three torpedo bombers came back,
但都中弹损坏了
and they're all shot up.
俯冲轰炸机呢
What about the dive bombers?
我们也许还能集结十几架
We can probably scrounge up a dozen.
麦克拉斯基  你中弹了
McClusky, you've been shot.
-长官  我可以飞  -可以个屁
- I can fly, sir. - The hell you can.
赶紧滚去医务室
Get your ass down to sick bay.
带上你信任的飞行员
Put the pilots you trust
把还能开的飞机都开出去
in any plane that can fly.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
您没事吧  长官
You okay, sir?
我没事
I'm fine.
贝斯特
克罗格
韦伯
罗伯茨
哈尔西
彭兰
施耐德
格林
拉姆塞
霍普金斯
范布伦
范迪弗
金史密斯
击落
失踪
有没有迪金森的消息
Has anybody heard from Dickinson?
没有
No.
暂时还没有
Not yet.
我知道你们刚从鬼门关走了一趟
Look, I know you boys have just been through hell.
但我们得回去  击毁敌军的最后一艘航母
But we gotta go back and hit the last carrier.
我看看能不能找到更多的人
I'll see if I can find more men.
穿衣服
Strap up.
我们要出发了
We're going back out.
对不起  长官  您还是找别人吧
I'm sorry, sir, but I think you need to find somebody else.
您不知道坐在后座上是什么感觉  长官
You don't know what it's like to be in the back seat, sir.
就好像您根本不在乎我们能不能活着回家
You fly like you don't care if we come home.
我也想回家
I wanna go home, too.
我也不想每次回家都只能跟妻子待那么几天
I wanna spend more than a few days at a time with my wife.
也想看着我的女儿长大
See my little girl grow up.
你说得对
And you're right.
如果我们回到战场上
If we go out there,
可能就回不来了
we probably aren't coming back.
但这是我们的职责
But this is our job,
我们必须坚守阵地
and we're the guys who have to hold the fort
等待驰援
till the cavalry arrives.
如果你真的不能飞了
Look, if you really can't fly,
我会去找别人
I'll find someone else.
但你应该坐回那架飞机上
But you should get back in that plane.
你的余生都会记得这一刻
You'll remember this moment for the rest of your life.
当人们把希望寄托在你身上的时候
And if you know that you came through
如果你挺过来了
when people were counting on you,
以后不管遇到什么  你都有能力面对
you'll be able to face anything.
我们已经经历了那么多  默里
We've come this far, Murray.
别让我独自回到战场
Don't make me go back out there without you.
我去给飞机做准备  长官
I'll warm her up, sir.
敌军损失了一艘航母  空中力量也有所削弱
我们要把他们引到战列舰的射程内  消灭他们
这是个大胆的计划
去给山口司令发电报
是
わかりました。
战场指挥官的电报
山本长官命令我们进攻
像武士一样  守护我们的荣耀
理应如此
下午4点56分
美军联合航空大队
做好准备  默里
Get ready, Murray.
这次我们可没法出其不意了
We're not sneaking up on them this time.
敌机来袭
Here they come!
注意高度
Altitude.
有零式战机追着我们
We've got Zeroes on our tail.
这是为了珍珠港
This is for Pearl.
没事了
You're gonna be okay.
谢了  伙计们
Thanks, boys.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
我离航母大概还有32公里就没油了
I ran out of fuel about 20 miles out.
迫降在菲尔普斯号旁边
Ditched next to the Phelps.
贝斯特呢
Where's Best?
那是他的一个僚机驾驶员
That's one of his wingmen.
他还没回来
He hasn't come back yet.
他可能是去飞一圈庆祝一下
He's probably just taking a victory lap.
是啊
Yeah.
正因为有迪克·贝斯特这样的人
Men like Dick Best are
我们才一定能赢下这场战争
the reason we're gonna win this war.
一定要回来  贝斯特
Come on, Best.
有消息吗
Any news?
孩子们都在后面
The kids are out back.
去吧
Go, go.
辛迪听到基地来的传言
Cindy heard a rumor from the base.
打了一场大战
There's a big battle
我们的一艘航母正在沉没
and one of our carriers is sinking.
飞行员呢
And the pilots?
听说伤亡惨重
It sounds like we lost a lot of them.
我去补个妆
I am gonna go powder my nose quickly.
日本人很可能要用战列舰进攻
The Japanese might charge with their battleships.
所以我们趁着夜色撤退
So we will withdraw for the night.
但到了早上  他们的舰队可能会超出我们的进攻范围
But their fleet might be out of range in the morning.
尼米兹命令我们审慎行事
Nimitz ordered us to be judicious.
我们今天大胜了一场
We won a great victory today.
别冒进
Let's not blow it.
妈的  迪克·贝斯特回来了
God damn it! Dick Best!
坚持住  小子
Hang in there, kid.
我们马上到家了
We're almost home.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
是吗  他们也这么说你
Yeah. They said the same thing about you.
很高兴他们是错的
I'm glad they were wrong.
司令的命令
Admiral's orders.
给默里吧
Give it to Murray.
他应得的
He earned it.
扶我一把
Give me your hand.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
医护兵
Corpsman!
快来个医护兵
I need a corpsman!
我扶着你
I got you.
走吧
Here we go.
你们都英勇地战斗过
但我们必须击沉这艘船  以免它落入敌手
这场战役的失利  责任在于将领  不在于你们
因此  我决定以身殉舰
我命令你们继续为天皇效忠
请允许我和您一起留下
很好
一起欣赏月色吧
全员弃舰
请允许我也留下来
你有这份心意  我很感动  但是你这样的年轻人必须离开
这是我最后的命令
布鲁诺怎么了
What happened to Bruno?
PBY飞过他已知的最后位置
PBY flew over his last known position.
救生筏上没有人
They spotted an empty life raft.
左舷鱼雷就位
Battle station torpedo port side.
方位90度瞄准飞龙号
Target Hiryu bearing ninety degrees.
请进
我们的侦察兵什么也没发现
美军航母一定是连夜撤走了
我们应该轰炸中途岛  美军没有战列舰
我们还可以赢下这场战争
你是将棋玩多了吧
我们不能为了挽回尊严  就赌上剩下的战舰
那么...
您的命令是什么  长官
日军正在撤退
The Japanese are retreating.
-我们赢了  -是的
- We won. - Yeah.
切斯特·威廉·尼米兹
指挥太平洋舰队
至1945年9月2日其麾下战舰
驶入东京湾接受日本投降
上帝保佑这些小伙子们
God bless those boys.
看来他们需要的只是一场堂堂正正的战斗
Turns out all they needed was a fair fight.
"蛮牛"威廉·哈尔西
}此后继续供职
成为美国海军历史上仅有的
被授予五星上将军衔的四人之一
格兰特将军回忆录
山本五十六
1943年  因行程信息被美国海军破译
于所罗门群岛座机被击落后身亡
看看我在你家里发现了什么
由于帮助杜立特和他的部下逃脱
约25万中国平民
被日本帝国陆军杀害
詹姆斯·哈罗德·杜立特
}回到美国后  罗斯福总统授予其荣誉勋章
当时参与空袭东京的80名机组人员每年相聚一次  直至最后一人在2019年故去
我们一半的兄弟
Half our men,
不是死了就是失踪
dead or missing.
嗯
Yeah.
威士忌怎么不喝了
Hey, whatever happened to that whiskey?
我在等你跟我一起从医务室溜出去呢
I was waiting for you to sneak out of sick bay.
我们做到了
We did it.
克拉伦斯·迪金森
后来成为海军少将  同时也是历史上
首位获得三枚海军十字勋章的飞行员
此为海军最高荣誉  嘉奖其英勇作战
小克拉伦斯·韦德·麦克拉斯基
最终成为航母舰长
直至今日  美国海军最优秀的攻击机中队
会被授予韦德·麦克拉斯基奖
等一下
Hang on, boys.
-多谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - Of course.
莱顿
Hey, Layton.
干得好
Hell of a job.
这场仗多亏了你们
You boys really came through for us.
埃德温·托马斯·莱顿
战争期间一直留在尼米兹身边
1985年出版了一本书
书中解释了罗彻福特和他的破译团队
在中途岛战役中发挥的关键作用
爸爸在那呢
There's Daddy!
走吧  宝贝
Come on, baby.
爸爸  爸爸
Daddy! Daddy!
宝贝
Hey, sweetie.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
怎么回事
What happened?
我吸入了烧碱
Apparently, I inhaled caustic soda.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我的肺受损了
My lungs are shot.
海军再也不会让我飞了
The Navy's never gonna let me fly again.
那就换一件擅长做的事情
Well, get good at something else.
你可以用后半辈子慢慢找
You have the rest of your life to figure it out.
"迪克"理查德·贝斯特
因其在中途岛海战中的表现荣获海军十字勋章
他是历史上仅有的两名
在一天内击中多艘敌军航母的飞行员之一
谨以此片
献给在中途岛战役中英勇作战的美日海军
大海铭记不朽